<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<DATA>
    <Description>Haakon VII, the first king of Norway after the dissolution of the union between Norway and Sweden, was actually a Danish prince. Originally called Prince Carl of Denmark, he changed his name when Norway made him king in 1905.
    </Description>

      <Description>Although it is one of the top oil exporters in the world, Norway is one of the countries with the highest petrol price.
    </Description>

      <Description>Norway handles driving violations very seriously. For instance, DUI is punished with a 30-day imprisonment, a fine that amounts to 10% of the offender’ annual income, and revocation of driver’s license.
    </Description>

      <Description>Norwegian newspapers receive financial aid from the government. Locally called pressestøtte, this media support aims to help newspapers that cannot sustain themselves.
    </Description>

      <Description>Norway observes a drinking tradition, wherein people drink to their hearts’ content on Fridays and Saturdays. This is aptly called helgefylla or “weekend binge drinking.”
    </Description>

      <Description>Norway keeps an underground seed bank on the archipelago of Svalbard. It was constructed to store and protect seeds from all possible threats such as war and disasters, hence the nickname “Doomsday” seed vault. The stored seeds are samples from all over the world.
    </Description>

      <Description>Grocery stores are not allowed to be open on Sundays, but gas stations and kiosks can (and they sell groceries).        
    </Description>

      <Description>You can buy beer in grocery stores, but you have to buy wine and hard liquor at one place and one place only-Vinmonopolet (which literally means ´Wine Monopoly´and closes quite early).
    </Description>

      <Description>Because food prices are so high in Norway, many Norwegians drive across the border to Sweden to shop.  These purchases amount to over 2 billion USD every year.
    </Description>

      <Description>It can cost in the thousands for Norwegian teenagers to get their license (minimum age 18).       
    </Description>

      <Description>Norwegians eat brown cheese (brunost)-one of my favorite things
    </Description>

      <Description>And lutefisk, fish soaked in lye (a chemical used in making soap)       
    </Description>

      <Description>speeding fines are often more serious than if a person is caught with drugs       
    </Description>

      <Description>Norway has voted against membership in the EU several times, but has implemented more EU directives than any other EU member state.       
    </Description>

      <Description>Norwegians love Grandiosa, cheap frozen pizza.
    </Description>

      <Description>Most Norwegians take a 4 week holiday during the summer.  This means that the country slows down a lot and if you are a tourist and you aren´t aware of this, you wonder where everyone is and why nothing is open….
    </Description>

      <Description>Norwegians are one of the only people in the world to hunt whales
    </Description>

      <Description>Norwegians eat American children´s Christmas figure, Rudolph (and it´s darn good!)       
    </Description>

      <Description>Norwegians do not typically smile or start talking to a stranger on the bus.  It is not considered rude to behave as such.       
    </Description>

      <Description>Bars stay open very late, but having drinks outside at the bar closes earlier than inside the bar.The bartender will take your full drink even if you just ordered it inside and walked outside.
    </Description>

      <Description>People that own a TV have to pay a yearly licence fee of approximately US$ 300.00. Failure to pay this fee will result in a hefty fine.         
    </Description>

      <Description>It’s illegal in Norway to buy sex, but not to sell sex. That means that a female prostitute will not be prosecuted for selling sex, but a male customer will.      
    </Description>

      <Description>Boxing was banned on TV up until the late eighties, because the director of the Norwegian Broadcasting Corporation at the time, Bjartmar Gjerde, considered the sport immoral.       
    </Description>

      <Description>Most Norwegian will claim Viking explorer Leif Erikson, the first European to set foot on the American continent in 1003 as Norwegian, even though he was born in Iceland.
    </Description>

      <Description>Many police stations in Norway are only manned during office hours, because of inadequate funding from the Government. Many of the police stations are closed during the weekends. People in need of police assistance are urged by an automatic phone message to contact the station during office hours.     
    </Description>
</DATA>