<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<DATA>
    <Description>The United States is divided into 50 states. However state each varies in size considerably. The smallest state is Rhode Island with an area of just 1,545 square miles (4,002 sq km). By contrast the largest state by area is Alaska with 663,268 square miles (1,717,854 sq km).
    </Description>

      <Description>Bristlecone pine trees, believed to be some of the world's oldest living things, are found in the western United States in California, Utah, Nevada, Colorado, New Mexico and Arizona. The oldest of these trees is in California. The oldest living tree itself is found in Sweden.
    </Description>

      <Description>The tallest mountain in the world is located in the United States Mauna Kea, located in Hawaii, is only 13,796 feet (4,205 m) in altitude above sea level, however, when measured from the seafloor it is over 32,000 feet (10,000 meters) high, making it taller than Mount Everest (Earth's tallest mountain above sea level at 29,028 feet or 8,848 meters).
    </Description>

      <Description>The lowest temperature ever recorded in the United States was at Prospect Creek, Alaska on January 23, 1971. The temperature was -80°F (-62°C). The coldest temperature in the contiguous 48 states was at Rogers Pass, Montana on January 20, 1954. The temperature there was -70°F (-56°C).
    </Description>

      <Description>The hottest temperature recorded in the United States (and in North America) was in Death Valley, California on July 10, 1913. The temperature measured 134°F (56°C).
    </Description>

      <Description>It costs more to buy a new car today in the United States than it cost Christopher Columbus to equip and undertake three voyages to the New World.
    </Description>

      <Description>During the American revolution, inflation was so great that the price of corn rose 10,000%, the price of wheat 14,000%, the price of flour 15,000%, and the price of beef 33,000%.        
    </Description>

      <Description>The U.S. national debt is now more than 22 times larger than it was when Jimmy Carter became president.
    </Description>

      <Description>The average supermarket in the United States wastes about 3,000 pounds of food each year.
    </Description>

      <Description>Approximately 48 percent of all Americans are currently either considered to be "low income" or are living in poverty.       
    </Description>

      <Description>In the UK, an average of about $3,500 is spent on healthcare per person each year.  In the United States, an average of about $8,500 is spent on healthcare per person each year.
    </Description>

      <Description>The average U.S. citizen drinks the equivalent of more than 600 sodas each year.       
    </Description>

      <Description>The only place in the United States where coffee is grown commercially is in Hawaii.       
    </Description>

      <Description>The United States has 845 motor vehicles for every 1,000 people.Japan only has 593 for every 1,000 people and Germany only has 540 for every 1,000 people.       
    </Description>

      <Description>Jimmy Carter was the first U.S. president to have been born in a hospital.
    </Description>

      <Description>In the middle of the last century, the United States was #1 in the world in GDP per capita.  Today, the United States is #13 in GDP per capita.
    </Description>

      <Description>In 2011, our trade deficit with China was more than 49,000 times larger than it was back in 1985.
    </Description>

      <Description>One out of every seven Americans has at least 10 credit cards       
    </Description>

      <Description>The United States puts a higher percentage of its population in prison than any other nation on earth does.       
    </Description>

      <Description>There are more unemployed workers in the United States than there are people living in the entire nation of Greece.
    </Description>

      <Description>Sadly, more than 52 percent of all children that live in Cleveland, Ohio are living in poverty.         
    </Description>

      <Description>Back in 1950, more than 80 percent of all men in the United States had jobs.  Today, less than 65 percent of all men in the United States have jobs      
    </Description>

      <Description>According to the Federal Reserve Bank of New York, approximately 167,000 Americans have more than $200,000 of student loan debt.       
    </Description>

      <Description>In 1940, 68.0% of all women in the 20 to 34 year old age group in the United States were married.  In 2010, only 39.2% of women in that age group were married.
    </Description>

      <Description>More people have been diagnosed with mental disorders in the United States than in any other nation on earth.     
    </Description>
</DATA>