<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<DATA>
    <Description>The Royal Bengal Tiger is Bangladesh’s national animal. This majestic creature has a roar that can be heard up to 3 kilometers away. Unfortunately, it is now an endangered species.
    </Description>

      <Description>More than half of Bangladesh’s population is composed of farmers.
    </Description>

      <Description>Despite the prevalence of farmers in Bangladesh, its export earnings come mainly from the garments industry.
    </Description>

      <Description>There are more than 2,000 periodicals and daily newspapers published in Bangladesh. However, the country’s average constant readership is only at 15%.
    </Description>

      <Description>Bangladesh is sometimes called “the playground of seasons” because it has six – not four – separate seasons, which it calls grismo (summer), barsha (rainy), sharat (autumn), hemanto (cool), sheet (winter), and bashonto (spring).
    </Description>

      <Description>With its size of 2,172,000 square kilometers, the Bay of Bengal is the largest bay in the world.
    </Description>

      <Description>In Bangladesh, the left hand is considered unclean, so always use your right hand when eating or passing food, drinks – or business cards!        
    </Description>

      <Description>The people of Bangladesh seldom smile. This is not because they are unfriendly but because smiling much is considered a sign of immaturity.
    </Description>

      <Description>India was the first country to Acknowledged Bangladesh as a newborn country. They did that on December 6th, 1971. 
    </Description>

      <Description>Dhaka is the capital of Bangladesh, while Bengali is the official language. However, English is also widely spoken and understood.       
    </Description>

      <Description>The currency of Bangladesh is Taka. 
    </Description>

      <Description>Bangladesh had been ruled by Britain and Pakistan. It declared independence from Pakistan on March 26, 1971.       
    </Description>

      <Description>Islam is the main religion practiced in Bangladesh.        
    </Description>

      <Description>The National Anthem of Bangladesh has been written by Rabindranath Tagore.        
    </Description>

      <Description>The national game of Bangladesh is known as Kabbadi. 
    </Description>

      <Description>Bangladesh is one of the most densely populated countries of the world and has a high rate of poverty and corruption.
    </Description>

      <Description>Apart from cyclones, Bangladesh regularly suffers from extensive flooding caused by monsoon rains and melting snows from the Himalayas
    </Description>

      <Description>There are a number of archaeological and historical sites in Bangladesh, which are know to date back as far as the third century BC.       
    </Description>

      <Description>Bangladesh is considered ground zero for climate change, already feeling its devastating effects. More than half the country is only 20 ft. above sea level.  By mid-century, approximately 1/5 of the country could be under water creating 20 million plus climate refugees.       
    </Description>

      <Description>Mostly 3 generations are living in one home. It is not in their culture to live separately, they like to be together, they are even afraid to move away from their parents, because they think they will feel lonely. That’s why some of the most popular questions that they ask me are: “Are you here with your parents? Are you here with your husband? You are alone??! Don’t you feel lonely?”
    </Description>

      <Description>When a younger person meets an elder person that he hasn’t seen for a while, he approaches him, touches elders feet and then touches his own chest and repeats this for 3 times to show the respect. Mean while the elder puts his hand on younger person’s head and gives blessing to him.         
    </Description>

      <Description>For Hindu women marriage symbols are many. They have a red line on the head where the hair spilt into half, red tip, 2 white bracelets and one metal. That’s how wives must look every day.      
    </Description>

      <Description>There are two typical questions that people ask each other every day:  “What did you eat? Did you take a shower?” Here everything is about eating! They eat a lot and in every meal there are lots of items on a table. And because it’s hot here, people sweat, so personal hygiene is very important.       
    </Description>

      <Description>They wear and buy rich clothes and they take care of their hygiene, but they don’t care much about their environmental cleanness. It’s not important to paint your house, walls and floor, to get rid of cobwebs, mice, cockroaches and other insects. Streets are very dirty. And no matter how educated they are all of them litter on streets. But I believe in new generation- they will be different, they will make changes.
    </Description>

      <Description>Traffic here is a perfect example that every chaos has its perfect order. There is only one rule: no rules! Red light – so what? Sign: can’t do something- so what? And on streets and roads you can find everything: starting from regular vehicles like cars, buses, trucks continuing with bikes, rickshaws, people, cows, goats, ducks and… But the roads are small, two way lines only. So, max speed is 70-80 km/h, but most probably sometimes you would even stop to let by some crazy truck or bus driver that is overtaking other vehicle.     
    </Description>
</DATA>