<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<DATA>
    <Description> Vegetation covers nearly 7 million square kilometres or 91 percent of Australia. 
    </Description>

      <Description>The largest Greek population in the world beside Athens in Greece can be found in Melbourne Victoria.
    </Description>

      <Description>Most of Australia's exotic flora and fauna cannot be found anywhere else in the world.    
    </Description>

      <Description>The Indigenous 'Dream Time' is the foundation for tens of thousands of years of spiritual aboriginal art, traditions, legends, myths, folklore and culture.
    </Description>

      <Description>More than 80 percent of Australians live within 100 kilometres of the coast making Australia one of the world's most urbanised coastal dwelling populations.
    </Description>

      <Description>Over 200 different languages and dialects are spoken in Australia including 45 Indigenous languages. The most common non-English spoken languages are Italian, Greek, Cantonese, Arabic, Vietnamese and Mandarin.
    </Description>

      <Description>The world's highest proportion of migrant settlers in a developed nation with over 25% of Australians born in another country.        
    </Description>

      <Description>Australia used to be a beer-drinking nation but its quaffing plunged to a 65-year low in 2010-2011 with only 4.23 litres consumed per person.
    </Description>

      <Description>Australia was the second country in the world to give women the right to vote in 1902.
    </Description>

      <Description>It has the highest rate of gambling in the world with over 80 percent of Australian adults engaging in gambling of some kind and 20 percent of the pokie machines in the world are found in Australia.       
    </Description>

      <Description>Kangaroo meat can be purchased from the supermarket, butcher and available on restaurant menus as a leaner and healthier alternative to beef or lamb with a 1-2 percent fat content.
    </Description>

      <Description>Surprisingly Australia is the most obese country in the world as of 2012 with a 26 percent obesity rate despite being a sport loving nation.       
    </Description>

      <Description>Approximately 1.35 trillion bottles of wine are produced by Australia.      
    </Description>

      <Description>Australian TV networks love cooking shows, airing one after another upon viewership success of My Kitchen Rules and MasterChef.        
    </Description>

      <Description>Canberra was selected as the capital because Sydney and Melbourne could not stop arguing which city should be the capital of Australia.       
    </Description>

      <Description>Ugg boots or as local call them 'very ugly boots' are an Australian design where a sheepskin has been turned inside out and made into a boot.        
    </Description>

      <Description>The only place in the world where you can still find the lung fish which is a living fossil from the Triassic period 350 million years ago.        
    </Description>

      <Description>The sports capital of the world has 70 percent of its total population participating at least once a week in a particular recreational activity or sport.       
    </Description>

      <Description>Despite having a convict colony history, Australia's homicide rate is 1.2 per 100,000 population compared to the 6.3 per 100,000 in the United States.         
    </Description>

      <Description>80 percent of Australians believe Australia has a strong culture and identity characterised by being down to earth, mateship, honesty, sports and multiculturalism based on research organised by the Australia Day Council of NSW in 2008. 
    </Description>

      <Description>Australians refer to English people as Pome, which is actually the acronym for Prisoners of Mother England.        
    </Description>

      <Description>Australia is the only continent without an active volcano.        
    </Description>

      <Description>Just over 25% of Australians were born in another country, making it the developed country with the highest proportion of migrant settlers in the world, aside from Luxembourg with a third of their population born elsewhere. Australia’s capital cities are where the highest proportions of new arrivals can be found and to say the country’s culinary landscape has benefited enormously from immigration is an understatement.        
    </Description>

      <Description>One of Australia’s former Prime Ministers, Bob Hawke, holds a Guinness World Record… not for some kind of political feat, but beer sculling! Fortunately it was well before his term as prime minister (1983-1991), occurring in 1963 during his university days at Oxford where he skulled 2.5 pints of beer in 11 seconds. To this day Bob Hawke is remembered fondly for his beer skulling antics, which he still wheels out in public now and then at cricket matches. Oh, Australia!
    </Description>

      <Description>Gondwanaland about 70 million years ago. It is considered to be the most stable land mass in the world, being free of any major mountain building events for the past 80 million years.         
    </Description>
</DATA>