<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<DATA>
    <Description>Iran is one of the few countries in the world where a couple can have a “temporary marriage.” These “marriages” can be valid for as short as an hour.
    </Description>

      <Description>Iranian transsexuals are allowed to undergo sex-change operations through a decree passed by the founder of the Islamic Republic himself, Ayatollah Ruhollah Khomeini.
    </Description>

      <Description>Being the largest producer of pistachio nuts, Iran is considered to be the pistachio capital of the world. Pistachio is the country’s second largest export next to oil and natural gas.
    </Description>

      <Description>As the women of Iran are prohibited from attending sporting events, some female football fans resort to cross-dressing to be able to watch live games.
    </Description>

      <Description>As a staunch advocate of family planning, Iran widely encourages the use of contraception. Moreover, to control population growth, Iran has established one of the few condom factories in the Middle East.
    </Description>

      <Description>Iran provides home and social security for approximately a million foreign refugees – the biggest number in a single country in the world. 
    </Description>

      <Description>Biblical characters Queen Esther and the prophet Daniel are buried in Iran.        
    </Description>

      <Description>Neckties are not worn or used in Iran.     
    </Description>

      <Description>Iranian households are forbidden to have satellite television.         
    </Description>

      <Description>The word mausoleum comes from the famous grave of King Mausolus. It is a 45-meter-tall marble structure covered with bas relief, is one of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World, and is found in Iran.       
    </Description>

      <Description>In Persian, the word Iran means “Land of the Aryans.”
    </Description>

      <Description>In 2012, Iran’s police chief announced that Google is a tool for spying. Additionally, the Iranian government wants to form a “national Internet” that would be under state control.k       
    </Description>

      <Description>In Iran, couples that want a marriage license are required to take an hour-long lecture on contraception.       
    </Description>

      <Description>Iran's capital and largest city, Tehran, has some of the worst air pollution in the world. An estimated 27 people die a day from air pollution-related diseases.       
    </Description>

      <Description>Approximately 14.2% of Iranians are obese, making it the 41st most obese country in the world. American Samoa is the largest, with 75% of its population obese. The United States is 6th in the world, with 33.9% of the population obese.
    </Description>

      <Description>In 1979, a group of Islamist students and militants overtook the American Embassy in Tehran. In support of the Iranian revolution, they demanded that the United States hand over Shah Pahlavi, who was dying of cancer and receiving medical treatment in the U.S. After 444 days, just minutes after President Ronald Reagan was sworn into office, the hostages were released.
    </Description>

      <Description>During the Iran-Iraq War, the United States officially supported Iraq and put pressure on other countries to stop selling weapons to Iran. However, the U.S. itself was later found to have been quietly selling weapons to the country. The resulting scandal was Iran-gate, or the Iran-Contra scandal
    </Description>

      <Description>Nearly half of Iran has an arid desert climate. It receives less than 4 inches of precipitation each year.       
    </Description>

      <Description>The Persian Gulf holds 60% of the world’s oil reserves. Iran alone has reserves of 125 billion barrels of oil, or 10% of the world’s total reserves. Iran pumps nearly 4 million barrels of oil each day       
    </Description>

      <Description>Approximately 70% of Iran’s population is under the age of 30.
    </Description>

      <Description>Iran is one of the world’s oldest continuous civilizations, with settlements dating back to 4000 B.C.         
    </Description>

      <Description>In Iran, a young girl who applies as a live-in maid is often required to submit medical documentation to establish whether her hymen is intact.      
    </Description>

      <Description>In Iran, men who do not marry stay with their natal family their entire life and are described as na-mard (not-men).       
    </Description>

      <Description>If a girl in Iran is sexually abused or harassed, blame typically falls on the girl’s mother, for not protecting her daughter, much more than on the offender.
    </Description>

      <Description>In Iran, females over the age of nine must wear a hijab in public. Additionally, religious rules do not allow women to wear bathing suits when men are present.     
    </Description>
</DATA>