<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<DATA>
    <Description>O Canada,” originally named “Chant national,” was written by Adolphe-Basile Routhier (French lyrics) and Calixa Lavallée (music) and first performed in Quebec City in 1880. The song was approved by the Parliament of Canada in 1967 as the unofficial national anthem and adopted officially on July 1, 1980.
    </Description>

      <Description>The border between Canada and the United States is officially known as the International Boundary. At 5,525 miles, including 1,538 miles between Canada and Alaska, it is the world's longest border between two nations.
    </Description>

      <Description>Canada is the largest producer of uranium in the world.
    </Description>

      <Description>At 3,855,103 square miles, Canada is the second largest country in the world, behind Russia
    </Description>

      <Description>The average life expectancy at birth for a Canadian is 81.16 years, the eighth highest in the world. The United States ranks 46th, at 78.14 years.
    </Description>

      <Description>According to the 2001 census, 42.6% of Canadians are Roman Catholic, 23.3% are Protestant, and 16% claim to have no religion.
    </Description>

      <Description>At the time it happened, the most expensive natural catastrophe in terms of property damage was a horrific hailstorm that struck Calgary on September 7, 1991. Insurance companies paid about $400 million to repair over 65,000 cars, 60,000 homes and businesses, and a number of aircraft.
    </Description>

      <Description>Canada contains 9% of the world's renewable water supply.
    </Description>

      <Description>The world's strongest current is found in the Nakwakto Rapids at Slingsby Channel, British Columbia. The current has been measured at speeds up to 18.4 miles per hour.
    </Description>

      <Description>Canada’s literacy rate is over 99%.       
    </Description>

      <Description>Tools that date back 20,000 years are the first evidence of history in Canada. They were found in caves on the Bluefish River in northern Yukon.
    </Description>

      <Description>In 1576 Martin Frobisher discovered the strait that bears his name.       
    </Description>

      <Description>Navigation of the north-west passage from the Atlantic to the Pacific was first achieved by the Norwegian explorer, Roald Amundsen in 1906.       
    </Description>

      <Description>Canada is famous for its ice wine – made from pressed frozen grapes. It’s usually served as a dessert wine.       
    </Description>

      <Description>Wine is produced in British Columbia, Ontario, Quebec and Nova Scotia.
    </Description>

      <Description>There are more doughnut shops in Canada per capita than any other country.
    </Description>

      <Description>Each Canadian eats an average of 190 eggs per year.
    </Description>

      <Description>Canadians drink more fruit juice per capita than any other country.       
    </Description>

      <Description>There are 15 world heritage sites in Canada. The one with the most interesting name is Head Smashed In-Buffalo-Jump.       
    </Description>

      <Description>Canada is home to 42 national parks, 167 national historic sites and four marine conservation areas.
    </Description>

      <Description>The US buys more oil from Canada than any other country.         
    </Description>

      <Description>Thirty two percent of Canadians are very happy, 55% are quite happy.      
    </Description>

      <Description>The heaviest rainfall ever recorded was in Buffalo Gap, Saskatchewan. On May 30, 1961 25 centimeters fell in less than an hour. That’s ten inches!       
    </Description>

      <Description>There are 522 airports with paved runways, 931 airports with unpaved runways.
    </Description>

      <Description>The license plate for cars, motorbikes and snowmobiles in Nunavut is in the shape of a polar bear.     
    </Description>
</DATA>