<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<DATA>
    <Description>Brazil has the 10th highest number of vehicle owners in the world.
    </Description>

      <Description>The world’s best and most delicious coffee is produced in Brazil.
    </Description>

      <Description>Brazil has the biggest rain forest of the world, the Amazon forest 
    </Description>

      <Description>Brazil has the 2nd highest Christian population in the world. 
    </Description>

      <Description>Almost 200 million people live in Brazil, which makes it the fifth largest country in the world in terms of population.
    </Description>

      <Description>About 1 million people who live in Brazil are Asian.
    </Description>

      <Description>Scientists have estimated that there may be up to four million species of plants and animals in Brazil.        
    </Description>

      <Description>Brazil has won the soccer world cup five times.
    </Description>

      <Description>Brazil has one of the New 7 Wonders of the World, the Christ Redeemer statue, located in Rio De Janeiro.
    </Description>

      <Description>Brazil is the largest country in Latin America.       
    </Description>

      <Description>Brazil has the eighth largest economy in the world.
    </Description>

      <Description>The Brazilian rainforest is 60% of the Amazon Rainforest.        
    </Description>

      <Description>Most Brazilians don't marry until their late twenties.       
    </Description>

      <Description>Every Brazilian city has at least one soccer stadium!       
    </Description>

      <Description>Brazil's Christ the Redeemer statue, located in Rio de Janeiro, is one of the 7 wonders of the modern world. 
    </Description>

      <Description>Brazil has the most species of monkeys in the world.
    </Description>

      <Description>Brazil has the greatest biodiversity of any country, and the most species of plants, freshwater fish, and mammals.
    </Description>

      <Description>The longest traffic jam in the world occurred on May 9, 2008 in São Paulo and stretched 165 miles. Traffic jams cost the city of São Paulo over $2.3 billion each year       
    </Description>

      <Description>The national day of Brazil is celebrated on September 7th each year as Independence Day. Brazil gained independence from Portugal on the 7th of September in 1822.       
    </Description>

      <Description>Officially, the legal drinking age in Brazil is 18, but it’s not enforced strongly.
    </Description>

      <Description>Though there is no official religion in Brazil, more than 75% of Brazilians are Roman Catholics.         
    </Description>

      <Description>Carnival is the most famous holiday in Brazil, and takes place 46 days before Easter. 80% of the annual consumption of beer and 70% of the annual foreign visitors come during this time.      
    </Description>

      <Description>Voting in the elections is compulsory in Brazil; everyone between the ages of 18 and 65 has to vote by law.       
    </Description>

      <Description>Over the 20th century, Brazil had a cumulative inflation rate of more than a quadrillion percent.
    </Description>

      <Description>Brazil’s homicide rate is 25 per 100,000 people, equivalent to being four times higher than the US crime rate.     
    </Description>
</DATA>