<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<DATA>
    <Description>Somalia is situated on the Horn of Africa, East of Ethipoia, along the Indian Ocean and the Gulf of Aden.
    </Description>

      <Description>Somali Shilling is the currency of Somalia. 
    </Description>

      <Description>Somalia comprises of 27 regions. 
    </Description>

      <Description>The Egyptians referred to Somalia as the Land of Punt that was rendered famous for frankincense and myrrh.
    </Description>

      <Description>Somalia and Arabic are the official languages of the country. Apart from these languages, Swahili, English and Italian are also widely spoken in the region. 
    </Description>

      <Description>Although the population of Somalia basically includes ethnic Somalis, it also contains some non-Somali ethnic minority groups like Benadiri, Bravanese, Bantus, Bajuni, Ethiopians, Indians, Persians, Italians and Britons.
    </Description>

      <Description>Somalia was colonized by both Britain and France before it gained independence in July 1, 1960.         
    </Description>

      <Description>The Portuguese were the first European explorers to visit Somalia.
    </Description>

      <Description>Somalia was one of those nations worst hit by the disastrous Indian Ocean Tsunami and Earthquake of 2004. Almost 289 people were reported dead or missing in the aftermath while hundreds of people were rendered homeless. 
    </Description>

      <Description>Somalia is one of those few African nations with the lowest HIV infection rates. However, almost 35% of children under the age of five in Somalia die every year due to epidemics and dehydration.       
    </Description>

      <Description>Somalia is the first African nation that was used for flying warplanes by the British. 
    </Description>

      <Description>Somalia is the only country in the world that does not possess a central form of government.        
    </Description>

      <Description>Somalis claim descent from Arabian families who settled on the Somali coast 1,000 years ago. While scholars still debate the origins of the Somalis and the time of their entry into present-day Somalia, there is no doubt that they were in the region several hundred years before the first recorded use of their names in the early 15th century. By the 12th century, the ancestors of some clan families were established in their present territories.      
    </Description>

      <Description>Somalia is the only Islamic country in the world that boasts of a 100% concentration of Sunni Muslims.        
    </Description>

      <Description>Somalia is the only African nation that can boast of the cheapest cellular tariff rates with some companies charging less than a cent per minute. 
    </Description>

      <Description>The cuisine of Somalia, albeit meat-centric and diverse, excludes Haram meat (prohibited meat), pork and alcohol in accordance with Islamic Law.
    </Description>

      <Description>Somalia is home to a population of about 10,085,638. 
    </Description>

      <Description>In the past nine months, pirates boarded 128 ships and fired at 52, with 70 vessels reportedly thwarting attacks. Pirates used guns in 137 incidents and knives in 66, killing one crew member, injuring 27 and taking 773 hostages, according to the IMB.       
    </Description>

      <Description>Somalia has the world's lowest health budget at 1.5% of it's Gross Domestic Product.       
    </Description>

      <Description>Somalia’s economy is mostly agricultural, based primarily on livestock and secondarily on crops. About 60% of the population in Somalia are pastoralists or agropastoralists, and about 20% were agriculturalists. Except for a small number of Somalis who rely on fishing, the remainder of the population are urban dwellers, employed as government workers, shopkeepers, factory workers, and traders. Pastoralists raise camels, cattle, sheep, and goats. While agropastoralists rely on a mixture of herding and farming.
    </Description>

      <Description>Loyalty and devotion to the family is important, and families always help each other when in need.     
    </Description>

      <Description>Somali people are usually tall and slender. Men often wear a flowing plaid "ma'awiis" or kilt or pants.      
    </Description>

      <Description>Children poverty is at 92 percent, and only 5 percent of the community have college or university degrees, while 40 percent of its youth do not go to school full-time.       
    </Description>

      <Description>Fourty percent of the recently arriving Somali population are affected by one or more kinds of intestinal parasites.
    </Description>

      <Description>The average life expectancy of an average Somali is 43-47 years. Traditionally, mental illness is believed to be caused by spirit possession or as a punishment from God. After a child is born, the new mother and baby stay indoors at home for 40 days, a time period known as afatanbah. Also, diapering is not common in the rural or poorer part of Somalia. When the baby is awake, the mother will hold a small basin in her lap and then hold her baby in a sitting position over the basin at regular time intervals.      
    </Description>
</DATA>