<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<DATA>
    <Description>Israel has the highest ratio of university degrees to the population in the world.
    </Description>

      <Description>Israel produces more scientific papers per capita than any other nation by a large margin -109 per 10,000 people - as well as one of the highest per capita rates of patents filed.
    </Description>

      <Description>In proportion to its population, Israel has the largest number of startup companies in the world. In absolute terms, Israel has the largest number of startup companies than any other country in the world, except the US (3,500 companies mostly in hi-tech).
    </Description>

      <Description>Israel has the highest average living standards in the Middle East.The per capita income in 2000 was over $17,500, exceeding that of the UK.
    </Description>

      <Description>In 1984 and 1991, Israel airlifted a total of 22,000 Ethiopian Jews at risk in Ethiopia to safety in Israel.
    </Description>

      <Description>srael has the third highest rate of entrepreneurship - and the highest rate among women and among people over 55 - in the world.
    </Description>

      <Description>Israel has more museums per capita than any other country.        
    </Description>

      <Description>Israeli scientists developed the first fully computerized, no-radiation, diagnostic instrumentation for breast cancer.
    </Description>

      <Description>In the days of Abraham, Jerusalem was called Shalem. 
    </Description>

      <Description>The First Temple was overseen by 3,300 men and built by 150,000 Jewish workers.        
    </Description>

      <Description>King David was buried on Mount Zion. 
    </Description>

      <Description>There are over 30,000 volunteer workers in Jerusalem       
    </Description>

      <Description> Family is central to Israeli life, with a great deal of attention given to children .Married children often live near the parents, and expect to care for the elderly parents .       
    </Description>

      <Description>To leave a body unburied for an extended period of time is considered disrespectful; therefore, in keeping with the principle of k'vod ha-met, Judaism mandates that burial should take place as soon as possible after the death, preferably within 24 hours.       
    </Description>

      <Description>The cell phone was developed in Israel by Motorola-Israel. 
    </Description>

      <Description>Voice mail technology was developed in Israel.
    </Description>

      <Description>Dairy products cannot be cooked or eaten with meat or poultry
    </Description>

      <Description>Only fish with scales and fins can be eaten and no shellfish .       
    </Description>

      <Description>Israel, of course, is known in the Bible as the "land of milk and honey." But for a long time, the country did not have a recognized culinary heritage. Thankfully, however, today Israel is widely credited with a rich and distinctive cuisine—one reflecting the diversity of Israeli society, but with roots deeply planted in Jewish and regional customs…       
    </Description>

      <Description>Another widespread trend is the large Israeli breakfast, composed of cheeses, salads, olives, distinctive Israeli bread, juice and coffee. Israel's loaded-down breakfast tables are based in the country's Biblical heritage: in Genesis, the patriarch Abraham and his wife, Sarah, set the standard for Jewish hospitality by searching out travel-weary guests, strangers, to be lavishly feted in their tent
    </Description>

      <Description>In Israel, lunch is the principal meal of the day, served at noontime when children return home from school. Most Israelis eat lightly in the evening, with dinner possibly consisting of dairy products, salads or eggs. Like in Europe, however, bread is often a part of every meal of the day; this, perhaps, might interest "low-carb" dieters, since Israelis, especially the young, are among the most fit in the Western world!         
    </Description>

      <Description>Jericho is the oldest continuously inhabited town in the world.      
    </Description>

      <Description>Israel is the only nation in the world that entered the 21st century with a net gain in it’s number of trees.       
    </Description>

      <Description>The Dead Sea is the lowest surface point on earth, at about 1,373 feet below sea level.
    </Description>

      <Description>The Sea of Galilee, at 695 ft. Below sea level, is the lowest freshwater lake in the world.     
    </Description>
</DATA>