<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<DATA>
    <Description> 99% of the Afghan population are Muslims (84% Sunni/15% Shia).Only one Jewish man lives in Afghanistan.
    </Description>
      <Description>Afghanistan has over 90,000 police. However, many are corrupt. Nearly 20% of them test positive to illegal drugs and they often demand bribes from people and businesses.
    </Description>
      <Description>The two most commonly spoken languages in Afghanistan are Persian (also called Dari) and Pashto.
    </Description>
      <Description>Very few people in Afghanistan (around 1.5% of the population) have internet access.
    </Description>
      <Description>There are many natural resources in Afghanistan that are yet to be mined. These include gold, silver, copper, zinc, iron ore, emeralds, uranium, salt, sulfur and coal. The US Pentagon believes that these minerals could be worth as much as US$1 trillion.
    </Description>
      <Description>Afghan rugs are very popular around the world.
    </Description>
      <Description>Afghanistan is known for growing some of the best melons, grapes, apricots, pomegranates, dried fruit and nuts in the world.
    </Description>
      <Description>Due to non-stop wars in the country for about 30 years, there are over 1 million handicapped or disabled people in the country.
    </Description>
      <Description>Like Americans, Afghans drive on the right hand side of the road.
    </Description>
      <Description>Afghanistan has very hot summers and very cold winters.
    </Description>
      <Description>There is only one doctor per every 5,000+ people.
    </Description>
      <Description>There is no AIDS in Afghanistan.
    </Description>
      <Description>There is only one telephone for every 333 people.
    </Description>
      <Description>There is only one radio for every 8 people.
    </Description>
      <Description>There is only one television for every 85 people.
    </Description>
      <Description>Afghanistan is 90% dependent on aid as it rebuilds.
    </Description>
      <Description>There is about one car for every 500 people and only 1/4th of all roads are paved.
    </Description>
      <Description>Some 92% of the world’s heroin comes from poppies grown in Afghanistan.
    </Description>
      <Description>Only 2 in 5 schools in Afghanistan have buildings.
    </Description>
      <Description>Afghanistan’s life expectancy is 44.2 years (44.4-women) 44 for men.
    </Description>
      <Description>There is a KFC in Kabul, however it is Kabul Fried Chicken.  The sign is a bit ridiculous.  The English words are simply written in Persian script.  The Persian word for chicken is 'murgh' but those crazy marketing geniuses have just written 'chicken.'   I'm also not sure if this is a genuine franchise or not.  I strongly suspect the Colonel's copyright has been infringed here.
    </Description>
      <Description>A British soldier who was meeting some Afghan army counterparts in Kabul in 2006 was interrupted by some Afghans civilians who had come to lodge a complaint.  The soldier was quite disconcerted as the Afghans were making their feelings felt very strongly.  They had come to protest about the burning down of the bazaar in Kabul.  The British officer immediately thought "oh God, what have the Paras done now!"  His Afghan counterparts quickly put him at ease and told him that they were protesting about the burning down of the bazaar in 1842!   Afghans have long memories.
    </Description>
      <Description>Alexander the Great thought the Kafiristanis were descendedfrom the god Dionysus (the god of wine) because their wine was so good and their hair and skin was lighter than other tribes around them. Many just assumed this was rubbish but anthropologists now believe that there was some sort of European migration several thousand years ago. Have a look at these kids.  This pic was taken in 2002.  I think they look Irish, they certainly don't look Greek to me.  The Greeks did leave their legacy and one of the high mountains in Nuristan/Kafiristan is called Qala Iskandariya - Fort of Alexander.  
    </Description>
      <Description>The main mountain range in Afghanistan is the Hundu Kush.  It is a massive range with mountains ataround 24,000 feet.  ‘Kush’comes from the verb ‘kushtan’ which means ‘to kill.’  Hindu Kush means ‘Hindu Killer.’  Mountaineering tourism has become very popular in recent years, Hindu killing is a thing of the past.
    </Description>
      <Description>Greece contributes around 80 soldiers to the Afghan ISAF Mission.  Ireland contributes seven; I don't know what they're doing but I'm telling you those boys look Irish. 
    </Description>
</DATA>